

Martin Maca Junior Software Developer

## **Contact details**

**\( +420 601 531 920 \)** 

remote, willing to relocate

### Core Skills

- Programming
- CAD design
- Design of special-purpose machines
- Project planing
- Scheaduling
- Client presentations

# **Professional Profile**

I have a combined 8 years of experience in different fields of industrial automation. From machine design, programming machine logic, designing and programming HMI systems, to servicing industrial robots and machines. I have good proficiency in a range of CAD software, high level of proficiency in programming Epson industrial robots, I also have experience programming PLCs in Structured Text, a standardized IEC 61131-3 language. I am very passionate about and have a varying degree of experience with standard software development. Programming languages in which I have used to in the past include C++, Java, HTML and Processing.

# **Career Summary**

Feb 2023 - Present

Internac Solutions, s.r.o., Kuřim Czech Republic

Research and Development Specialist

Outline

Internac Solutions is a non-profit organization focused on helping SMEs within our region with automation and digitalization. My primary role in the company is to help identify processes suitable for automation, draft a practical and economical solution, test the proposed solution in our testbed, and communicate my analysis with customers.

2017 - 2022

Opticontrol s.r.o., Lelekovice Czech Republic

Programmer and design Engineer

Outline

Opticontrol is a company focused on industrial automation. Main area of focus is single machine design and manufacturing, mainly for the automotive industry. I was tasked with designing and programming of the single purpose machines, and I got to experience the complete lifecycle of each machine.

2016 - 2017

Balak Stroje Tišnov s.r.o., Tišnov

Machine technician

Outline

Small family company focused on designing and building machining tools. Their main customers are companies in the automotive industry.

Jan 2015 - Dec 2015 Global Languages, Pereira, Colombia

Engligh teacher

Outline

Teaching English to kids and adults as part of a AIESEC student intership program.

### **Education**

- Bachelor degree | Brno University of Technology | 2011 2014 High School Graduate | Grammar School Tišnov | 2006 2010 Student Exchange Program | Bountiful High School, Utah, USA | Jan 2008 Jul 2008

### Certificates

- Universal Robots Advanced training | 2023
- Epson Robots Maintenance | 2019 National Welding Certificate MAG 135 1.1 | 2016